Horton hears more than anyone believes.
Horton Hears a Who! is a animation, comedy, family
film directed by Steve Martino.
An imaginative elephant named Horton hears a faint cry for help coming
from a tiny speck of dust floating through the air.
Horton suspects there may be life on that speck and despite a surrounding community, who
thinks he has lost his mind, he is determined to save the tiny particle.
Horton (voice), played by Jim Carrey.
Mayor (voice), played by Steve Carell.
Kangaroo (voice), played by Carol Burnett.
Vlad (voice), played by Will Arnett.
Morton (voice), played by Seth Rogen.
Councilman / Yummo Wickersham (voice), played by Dan Fogler.
Horton Hears a Who!
is a 2008 American animated adventure comedy film
based on the 1954 children's book by Dr.
Produced by Blue Sky Studios, the film was directed by Jimmy Hayward and
Steve Martino and written by Cinco Paul and Ken Daurio.
It stars the voices of Jim Carrey and Steve Carell as Horton the Elephant and Mayor Ned McDodd, respectively,
alongside Carol Burnett, Will Arnett, Seth Rogen, Dan Fogler, Isla Fisher, Jonah Hill, and Amy Poehler.
The plot follows Horton, an eccentric elephant who discovers the city
of Whoville, led by Mayor McDodd, on a tiny speck.
Horton begins a journey to take the speck to safety while a group
of animals led by the Kangaroo attempt to stop him.
The film is the fourth screen adaptation of the book, following the 1970 Chuck Jones television
special, the 1987 Soviet animated short, and the 1992 Russian animated short.
Production began in 2005 after Chris Meledandri secured the rights to the book from Seuss's widow Audrey Geisel, who
provided the studio with Seuss's original sketches and materials and was credited as an executive producer.
Recurring Blue Sky collaborator John Powell composed the film's musical score.
Horton Hears a Who!
was released theatrically in the United States on
March 14, 2008, by 20th Century Fox.
The film was well-received by critics, who praised its writing, visuals, and faithfulness to
the source material, and grossed $298 million on a budget of $85 million.
Horton Hears a Who!
was the first Dr.
Seuss film adaptation to be fully animated using CGI and the second to
feature Jim Carrey after How the Grinch Stole Christmas (2000).
The film explores themes of rescue, elephant, jungle, who, cartoon elephant.
The tone is lighthearted.